Madhav Trivedi

Software Engineer

madhavtrivedi.work17@gmail.com | in https://www.linkedin.com/in/madhavpt | 4 +91-9106655362 | A Pune, India

SUMMARY

As a software engineer with 4+ years of industrial exposure, I have strong problem-solving ability and expertise in Angular, JavaScript, SQL, .Net, PHP, and Python. I bring along experience working in an Agile environment, managing juniors, delegating responsibilities, building good connections with clients and stakeholders, engaging in effective communication to understand requirements, and delivering great solutions that exceed expectations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, SQL, Python, C#, PHP, Dart

Frameworks: Angular, Codelgniter, Laravel, Flask, Node JS, Express JS, .NET, .NET Core, Flutter

Libraries: React, jQuery, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib

Developer Tools: Git, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook

Others: Data structures and Algorithms, System Design, JWT, Problem solving, Debugging, Troubleshooting

SECONDARY SKILLS

Leadership, Team Collaboration, Adaptability, Interpersonal Communication, Delegation, Self-motivation, and Detail-oriented

WORK EXPERIENCE

Thinkbridge Software Pvt. Ltd.

Nov 2020 - Current

(Software Engineer)

Pune, MH

- Developed and managed Fintech applications, a Career Service Portal with 1M+ users, and a Product Subscription tool.
- Built a maintainable and scalable system with multilingual support (I18N/L10N) and optimized performance by handling data efficiently and implementing caching. Increasing client's revenue by 2x and expanding the application's global reach.
- Designed a high-performance system for handling a large dataset of 1M+ entries on Client side and improved the page performance by around 50%.
- Migrated a Monolithic (MVC) Architecture to Microservices, increasing application performance by 30-40%.
- Implementing CI/CD pipelines, code reviews, task delegation, and training new team members to ensure coding standards and quality.

Ubisoft India Jan 2020 - Nov 2020

(Junior Web Developer)

Pune. MH

- At Ubisoft India, I played a key role in designing responsive and seamless UI screens, developing APIs and middleware, optimizing databases, and overseeing the deployment, maintenance of code, and cron jobs on a Linux-based VM to ensure a comprehensive and efficient system.
- Built an automated system at Ubisoft India to streamline repetitive manual tasks performed by the HR team. Leveraged the cron jobs to execute scripts automatically based on specified conditions, resulting in a robust solution. Enhanced the work accuracy of the HR team by 10-15% and reduced manual workload by 80%.

iTalent India Management Consultants Pvt. Ltd. (Web Developer Intern)

May 2019 — June 2019

- Served as a dedicated and supportive intern in a fast-paced environment.
- While working with iTalent India, I had the opportunity to work on web development technologies including, PHP, Laravel, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, and MySql.

PROJECTS

- Portfolio Site | Skills: React, GitHub deployment, SSL Integration, DNS configuration, Hosting
- Tab's Archive | Skills: Problem Solving, System Design, Design Patterns, JavaScript, Project Management, Chrome API
- Curve (Covid-19 Cases monitoring mobile app) | Skills: Flutter, Dart, Firebase, Data Visualization
- Face Detection Attendance System | Skills: Python, OpenCV, Microsoft Azure Cognitive Services, SQL
- Fund GOGO | Skills: PHP, Laravel, HTML, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, Team collaboration, Leadership

CERTIFICATIONS

- > Data Structures and Algorithms GeeksForGeeks
- System Design from Low Level to High Level GeeksForGeeks
- J.P. Morgan's Software Engineering Virtual Experience Forage
- > Data Analytics with Python FreeCodeCamp
- Scientific Computing with Python FreeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures FreeCodeCamp
- > Back End Development and APIs FreeCodeCamp

ACHIEVEMENTS

- > Graduated with an **8.15 GPA from MIT Pune**.
- > Secured **3rd rank in the Smart India Hackathon 2019 at IIT Kanpur**. It provided an opportunity to work on a project that addressed a real-world problem while **collaborating with a team of 5 members**.
- > Selected as a placement coordinator and worked closely with the MIT Pune placement team to provide on-campus placement opportunities for students. We were successful in bringing over 75 companies on campus within 60 days and obtaining placements for over 90% of the targeted students.
- Organized a national-level hackathon (Technocon Lakshya 2019) at MIT Pune, which provided a platform for students to showcase their technical skills and innovations. I contributed by designing a few rounds of Hackathon, bringing the sponsors, and marketing the event on social media to reach as many students as possible across the nation. As a result, 250-300 students attended the event from 4 states.
- 2nd Position in a State Level Skating Competition at Gujarat (2007)

EDUCATION

MCA Computer Science - 8.15 CGPA

2017 - 2020

Maharashtra Institute of Technology (MIT), Pune, India

ONLINE PRESENCE

Portfolio: https://www.madhavtrivedi.com

Free Code Camp: https://www.freecodecamp.org/madhavtrivedi77
Hacker Rank: https://www.hackerrank.com/madhavtrivedi77

GitHub: https://github.com/Madhav-77

INTERESTS

Health & Fitness, Geopolitics, Investment & Trading, Astrophysics, Singing, Playing Guitar, Travelling, and Reading

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Gujarati, Marathi